<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Back to School</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 10:03:03 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 10:03:03 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pattern thingy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I eventually got something done!
The idea of the PatternRepeater project came up as I got some kind of building bricks made of wood from my father. On a long train ride or when I’m bored I like to scribble stuff and it usually ends up to be a kind of pattern so my dad made these bricks for me so I could adjust them on the table and play around. Unfortunately it was just very few ones. I had just come back from 31C3 where I had seen this augmented reality sandbox:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/qg6F-Hn_rog&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wished for  an application that would detect my bricks, repeat the pattern and project it to the table. I started to think of an algorithm that I have now finished prototyping in Processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically it works like this:
On mouseReleased I get the current position, snap it to a grid and add this newly created shape to a list I called initial shapes. They make up the fractal that will be repeated. 
I then sort this list based on the position going from left to right and up to down. 
For each shape in the list I determine the distance to the ‘parent’ shape, at list[i-1] and add it to this one as a child. 
I also get the maximum x and y distance, they make up the size for one pattern element, like a tile.
And then I draw, starting from the first list element and recursively going through the list, drawing one tile after the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/master/images/coding/_patternExample.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Pattern example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also draw the initial shapes in pink, they are not aligned with the generated ones. So on the screen its like two layers, the one to build up my ttile with the initial hspes and one that shows me the generated pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this as a kind of prove of concept that the algorithm works. I’m thinking of changing it in a way so the generated pattern would actually fit in with the initial ones. For that I think of moving the origin to the top left corner of my element and then draw to all four quadrants and mirror accordingly. But first there is a beach trip setup for tomorrow and today there is an acroyoga class…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chicarrida/PatternRepeater&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
And thanks to Stefan for finding my redrawing bug :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 12:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/jekyll/update/2015/03/28/title.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/jekyll/update/2015/03/28/title.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ah, well....</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not much coding going on right now, I could blame the weather or the view….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued wit my PatternRepeater, set up a new approach, still WIP. Sunday we had a Hackday. I joined a group that visualized data from &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinmarketcap.com/&quot;&gt;coinmarketcap&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org/&quot;&gt;D3&lt;/a&gt; - yeah! Result can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://cc.binaryage.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the it looks like its going to be more cloudy, meaning I could actually do some coding - on the other hand it also means I can go for a walk and explore Ubud - ah, well….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 14:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/jekyll/update/2015/03/24/Ah-well.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/jekyll/update/2015/03/24/Ah-well.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Journey begins tomorrow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Title says it all, my flight goes tomorrow and by Sunday evening, resp. midday I’ll be in Bali! &lt;em&gt;excited&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 19:13:32 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/jekyll/update/2015/03/13/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/chicarrida/chicarrida.github.io/blob/master/jekyll/update/2015/03/13/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
